# Akash Choudhuri

Address: Department of Computer Science, University of Iowa,

Iowa City, IA, 52246

Webpage: soothysay.github.io

## Research Interests

My primary research interest lies in the intersection of machine learning and deep learning with applications in the domain of healthcare. I have also recently explored the field of uncertainty quantification using Graph Neural **Networks**. My long-term research goal is to develop a scalable and comprehensive framework to predict the risk posed by patients in healthcare settings and propose mitigation strategies. I have a good understanding of data processing and analytics, deep learning, natural language processing, and statistics.

## **EDUCATION**

The University of Iowa

Doctoral Degree: Computer Science; GPA: 3.68/4.0

Institute of Mathematics and Applications

Master of Science: Mathematics with Data Science; GPA: 8.70/10

Birla Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics and Computing; GPA: 8.0/10

Iowa City, USA

January 2022 - Present

Email: akash-choudhuri@uiowa.edu

Github: github.com/Soothysay

Mobile: +1-319-259-3021

Bhubaneswar, India

July 2019 - July 2021

Mesra, India

July 2016 - June 2019

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, JAVA, R, C, MATLAB • Languages:

• Frameworks: Scikit, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Flask, H3, Pyspark, AWS

Tools: GIT, MySQL

## Professional Experience

## Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory

Livermore, USA

May 2023 - August 2023

- Intern, Data Science Summer Institute o Uncertainty Quantification of Weighted Link Prediction in Graphs (Summer Project): Researched and
  - Developed a conformal prediction algorithm to compute the uncertainty bounds of link prediction using GCNs at a feature level. I am currently working towards a publication. o Cardiac Electrocardiography using Machine Learning (DSSI Challenge Problem): Primarily worked on the
  - multi-class classification problem to classify irregular heartbeats from a time series data of heartbeats. Fine-tuned and created different ML Models like XGBoost and a hybrid MLP+Randomforest Classifier algorithm. Created a hybrid model that gave 12% gain in accuracy in the MIT-arrhythmia dataset.

**Data Sutram** Kolkata, India

Data Scientist July 2021 - December 2021

- o Optimized Algorithm for Delivery Management Systems: Created a real-time optimization algorithm to assign orders to delivery executives in last-mile delivery services.
- o Dynamic Footfall: Found metrics to compute dynamic footfall of places in India using internet devices ping data.
- Improved geo-coding Wrapper: Created a wrapper method that uses Google APIs to geocode Indian addresses.

Solytics Partners Pune, India Consultant (Data Science) May 2021 - July 2021

- o Financial Model Testing: Worked on validating a Credit Risk Model of the World Bank and performed additional stress testing experiments.
- o Technical Recruiter: Was associated with technical recruiting of employees in USA and also conducted campus recruitment process in Indian universities

Solytics Partners

Remote

Intern (Data Science)

March 2020 - April 2021

- o Auto ML Model: Worked on creating various pipelines for creating an Auto ML and Deep Learning platform for credit risk scoring.
- o Pyspark integration with Keras Models: Worked on creating Pandas UDFs to customize Neural Networks on Spark.

#### Current Projects

- Heterogeneous Hypergraphs for predicting Healthcare Associated Infection Incidence Rates: (Work in Progress) Creating a hypergraph-based deep learning method to predict levels of disease incidence based on heterogeneous interactions of patients with healthcare entities over time.
- Optimized Vaccine Allocation model to Combat COVID-19: (In submission AAAI 2024) Using real-time USA mobility data to optimize vaccine allocation across counties in USA.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Choudhuri, A. Jang, H., Segre, A.M., Polgreen, P., Jha, K. and Adhikari, B.: Continually-Adaptive Representation Learning Framework for Time-Sensitive Healthcare Applications, In publication Process, Proceedings of The 32<sup>nd</sup> ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, 2023.
- Choudhuri, A.: "A Hybrid Machine Learning Model for Estimation of Obesity Levels" In Data Management, Analytics and Innovation: Proceedings of ICDMAI 2022, Springer Nature (https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-19-2600-6<sub>2</sub>2) .

## IMPORTANT TALKS

- CDC MIND Group Meeting 2023: Presented initial motivations about the integration of clinical notes for CDI incidence prediction and CCMI prediction and presented the results of our paper titled "Continually-Adaptive Representation Learning Framework for Time-Sensitive Healthcare Applications".
- Summer Slam 2023: Presented initial approach to computing uncertainty bounds for weighted link prediction in graphs at the Summer Slam at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory.
- Tutorial Series 49th Annual Conference of the Odisha Mathematical Society, 2020: Presented an introductory tutorial on using ANNs for credit risk estimation.

#### ACADEMIC SERVICE

- International workshop on Epidemiology meets Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery (epiDAMIK @ KDD): Program Committee Member and reviewer of the conference for 2022 and 2023.
- Informatics in Medicine Unlocked (IMU): Reviewer for the journal in 2022 and 2023.
- IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining (ASONAM): Reviewer for the 2024 edition of the conference.

## Honors and Awards

- UIOWA CS Department Travel Grant:: Full funding received to present research works in 2023.
- Focus Areas in Science and Technology Summer Fellowship:: From the Indian Academy of Sciences from May-June, 2019
- Summer Research Fellowship:: From the Indian Academy of Sciences from May-July, 2018.
- Indo-German Spring School on Algorithms and Big Data: Obtained full scholarship to attend the workshops and discussion sessions in 2020.

## Relevant Courses

- CS: 4980: Computational Epidemiology
- DATA: 4750: Probabilistic Statistical Learning
- ECE: 5995: Data Mining
- CS: 5630: Cloud Computing Technology
- CS: 5350: Design and Analysis of Algorithms
- ECE: 5995: Generative AI Tools
- BIOS: 7600: Statistical Analysis of Network Data

## References

- $\bullet \ \ \textbf{Bijaya} \ \ \textbf{Adhikari:}: \ Assistant \ Professor, \ Department \ of \ Computer \ Science, \ University \ of \ Iowa. \ bijaya-adhikari@uiowa.edu$
- Kishlay Jha:: Assistant Professor, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Iowa. kishlay-jha@uiowa.edu